Mss.506.44.At4
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Paris, Nov. 8, 1828; 8-3/4x7; Babinet, M. (Jacques), 1794-1872; Demonferrand, Jean Baptiste Firmin, 1793-1844
    Versailles, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning his course in physics and references to Pouillet.
  - Letter to Lenoir, [1828 ca.]
  - Receipt for 600 francs to l'Athénée de Paris, March 30, 1829; 4-1/4x6-1/2; Blainville, H.-M. Ducrotay de (Henri-Marie Ducrotay), 1777-1850
  - Letters to [André Marie] Ampère, July 25, 1829; 10x8; Académie des sciences, arts et belles-lettres de Caen
    Caen, A.L.S.: Hébert. 1p.,end. In French. Notifies him that his diploma as associate of the académie is forwarded.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre Lenoir], Oct. 16, 1829; 10x7; Binet, Jacques Philippe Marie, 1786-1856
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning lectures at school.
  - Letter to l'Athénée de Paris, Paris, Nov. 14, 1829; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Demonferrand, Jean Baptiste Firmin, 1793-1844
    Versailles, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Names substitutes for teaching for him.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 22, 1829; 8x5; Prévost, Constant, 1787-1856
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Has decided to publish the story.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Paris, Dec. 6, 1829; 9-1/2x7; Demonferrand, Jean Baptiste Firmin, 1793-1844
    Versailles, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning the teaching of physics at l'Athénée de Paris.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Feb. 25, 1830; 10x8; Lepan, Edouard Marie Joseph, 1767-1836
    Paris, L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks him to subscribe to a new publication.
  - Letter to [André Ampère], May 5, 1831; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Navier, M. (Claude-Louis-Marie-Henri), 1785-1836
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning mémoires for "l'academie."
  - Receipt for 300 francs from l'Athénée de Paris, June 6, 1831; 4-1/2x6-3/4; LeChevalier, Jean Baptiste, 1752-1836
  - Receipt for 300 francs from l'Athénée de Paris, June 21, 1831; 4-1/2x7; LeChevalier, Jean Baptiste, 1752-1836
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Nov. 17, 1831; 9x6-3/4; Mohl, Jules, 1800-1876
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Will not be able to write.
  - Letter to the Minister of commerce and public works, Nov. 25, 1831; 12x8; Peigné, A de, d.1869
    L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Wants his book used in institutions of correction, etc.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Feb. 2, 1832; 7-3/4x5; Naudet, J. (Joseph), 1786-1878
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. States that the Sum is 90 francs.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 23, 1832; 7-1/2x5 and 10-1/2x8; Andouin, Jean Victor, 1797-1841
    A.L.S. with initials. 4p.and 4p.enc. In French. Entomological subjects.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, March 5, 1832; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Ozanam, J. A. F., 1772-1836
    Lyon, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Concerning his son, Frédéric.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, April 11, 1832; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Ozanam, J. A. F., 1772-1836
    Lyon, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Hopes his son will leave Paris for Lyon and asks Ampère to urge the boy to do so.
  - Letter to ----, June 22, 1832; 8-1/4x6-1/2; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Thanks for statement which he worked out for the general assembly.
  - Receipt to Lenoir for 300 francs from the Athénée, July 26, 1832; 4-3/4x7-1/4; LeChevalier, Jean Baptiste, 1752-1836
  - Letter to Monsieur Noel, Paris, Oct. 4, 1832; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Peclet, E. (Eugène), 1793-1857
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Will not accept the proposition.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Oct. 15, 1832; 6-1/4x4; Filon, Charles Dësiré Auguste, 1800-
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Must have his plan accepted, or else he will not teach.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Oct. 28, 1832; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Ozanam, Frédéric, 1813-1853
    Lyon, A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Returns to Paris. On same leaf is letter from J.A.F. Ozanam to Ampère; Oct.28,1832.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Oct. 28, 1832; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Ozanam, J. A. F., 1772-1836
    Lyon, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Thanks for favors to his son. Prizes from the Institute. On same leaf as letter from A.F.Ozanam to Ampére; Oct. 28, 1832.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Nov. 3, 1832; 8x5; Guigniault, Joseph-Daniel, 1794-1876
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning an engagement for tomorrow.
  - Letter to Monsieur de Roquefort, Dec. 13, 1832; 10x8; Royer-Collard, Pierre Paul, 1763-1854
    Paris, L.S. 1p. In French. Notifies him of an award of 500 francs.
  - Receipts to Lenoir for francs from l'Athénée, Aug. 22, 28, 1832; 4-1/4x7; LeChevalier, Jean Baptiste, 1752-1836
    Paris, D.S. 1p. In French. 2 items on 1 leaf.
  - Receipts to Lenoir for payments from l'Athénée de Paris, June 19, 29, 1832; 5x7-1/2; LeChevalier, Jean Baptiste, 1752-1836
    Paris, A.D.S. 2 items. In French.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Paris, April 30, 1833; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Prévost, Constant, 1787-1856
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. with note on stones. In French. Concerning his courses which he will teach.
  - Letter to [André] Ampère, July 18, 1833; 10-1/2x8; Ozaneaux, Jean Georges, 1795-1852
    Toulouse, L.S. 2p. In French. Finances. Friendly letter. Refers to Matter.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Sept. 29, 1833; 8-3/4x7; Turpin, P.J.F. (Pierre Jean François), 1775-1840
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Transcription of letter of de Candolle to Flourens. Sends transcription of letter about his [Turpin's] work.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Oct. 22, 1833; 11x8-1/2; Pinault
    Issy, A.L.S. 2p.and add., In French. Friendly letter. Physics.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Nov. 21, 1833; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Mathieu de Dombasle, C.J.A. (Christophe Joseph Alexandre), 1777-1843
    L.S. 2p.,end. In French. Concerning rural economics.
  - Letter to [André Marie Ampére], Jan. 2, 1834; 8x5-1/4; Vincent, Alexandre Joseph Hidulphe, 1797-1868
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Forwards publications. Recommends his attention to certain theorems.
  - Letter to Baron Nougarède de Fayet, Paris, March 9, 1834; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Raymond, Françoise, fl 1821-1823
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Wishes to lecture on Shakespeare in English.
  - Letter to [André] Ampère, Paris, March 20, 1834; 8x5; Monge, Eugène de
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Announces publication.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Clermont, May 25, 1834; 5x4; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    [Luzy,]. A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. His visit to Luzy and results. Business.
  - Letter to J[ean] J[acques] Ampère, July 13, 1834; 8x5; Guigniault, Joseph-Daniel, 1794-1876
    Paris, L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning lessons.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Sept. 22, [1834?]; 8x5; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Education.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Dec. 15, 1834; 7-1/2x5; Laurent, Jean Louis Maurice, 1784-1854
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning a publication, and he cannot visit with him this evening.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Jan. 27, 1835; 8x5; Guigniault, Joseph-Daniel, 1794-1876
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Presents publication.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Paris, Feb. 7, 1835; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Prévost, Constant, 1787-1856
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning a meeting of geologists.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampére, Paris, Feb. 10, 1835; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Payen, Anselme, 1795-1871
    Paris, L.S. 1p.and add. In French. School event listed.
  - Letter to l'Athénée de Paris, May 26, 1835; 8x6-1/4; Montémont, Albert, 1788-1861
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Presents publication.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, Aug. 20, 1835; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Raymond, Françoise, fl 1821-1823
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Presents publication on mathematics.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Nov. 7, 1835; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning future lessons.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 20, 1835; 8x5; Audouin, Jean Victor, 1797-1841
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Asks for dates to be changed for lectures.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, March 9, 1836; 7-1/4x5; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning their hour to leave.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, March 16, 1836; 6x4; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    A.L.S 1p.and add. In French. Will see him at 7:30 AM.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, May 6, 1836; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Ozanam, Frédéric, 1813-1853
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Is too busy to see him as requested.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, May 11, 1836; 8x6-1/4; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Will delay departure until the date requested, but must return the date set.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, July 3, 1836; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Ozanam, Frédéric, 1813-1853
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning his notices on Ampére.
  - Letter to ----, June 29, 1837; 8x5; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning Lenoir and other people being considered for a post.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, July 28, 1837; 8x6; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Is ill and desires him to visit.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Aug. 5, [1837]; 8x6; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Will discuss certain business with him when he visits. Business of l'Athènèe.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Paris, Aug. 15, 1837; 8x5-1/4; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning a meeting with him at a future date.
  - Letter to ----, Oct. 30, 1837; 8x5 and 7-1/2x5; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    A.L.S. 2p.and enc.of 2p. In French. Lectures on homeopathatic medicine. His displeasure with l'Athénée de Paris.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Paris, Nov. 20, 1837; 9-1/2x7 and 7-1/2x5; Babinet, M. (Jacques), 1794-1872
    Pairs; A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end.with note of 1p. In French. Concerning his course on meteorology to be taught at l'Athénée de Paris.
  - Letter to ----, Nov. 24, 1837; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Duhamel, M. (Jean Marie Constant), 1797-1872
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Regrets he cannot teach a course at l'Athénée de Paris.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Paris, Dec. 20, 1837; 7-1/2x5; Rienzi, Louis Grègoire Domény de, 1789-1843
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Concerning a course in geography at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to Monsieur Comartin, March 29, 1838; 8-3/4x7; Rienzi, Louis Grègoire Domény de, 1789-1843
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p.,end. In French. Will teach at l'Athénée, but for money. Refers to Cuvier and La Harpe.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Paris, Nov., 1838; 8-3/4x6-1/2; Blainville, H.-M. Ducrotay de (Henri-Marie Ducrotay), 1777-1850
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning lectures.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris], March 20, 1839; 8x5; Montémont, Albert, 1788-1861
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Presents publication.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Paris, June 8, [1839]; 7-3/4x5; Nougarède de Fayet, Auguste, 1811-1853
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Will subscribe for 6,000 francs and help acquire equipment for teaching.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris], Oct. 21, 1839; 10-1/4x7-1/2; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Could not lecture last year, but can lecture this year.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Paris, Nov. 4, 1839; 8x5; Payen, Anselme, 1795-1871
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. May teach at l'Athénée next session.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris], Nov. 4, 1839; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Will lecture.
  - Letter to Dr. C. James, March 15, 1841; 9-1/2x7-1/2; James, C.
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Wishes to publish articles on use of galvanism in medicine, but he has already utilized the subject in lectures at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to Dr. C. James, March 15, 1841; 9-1/2x7-1/2; James, C.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon, Dec. 7, 1841; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Concerning dates and hours for lectures at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to [Anselme] Payen, Feb. 27, 1842; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Dailly
    Paris, L.S. 1p. Note from Payen to Goujon on same page, In French. Concerning a course at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to [Pierre Simon] Ballanche, Paris, April 23, 1842; 6x4; Lacretelle, Charles, 1766-1855
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Wishes his relative could be appointed to a place on the committee.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, Dec. 10, 1842; 8x4-3/4; Becquerel, Alexandre Edmond, 1820-1891
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Wishes his name to appear with his brother's and not simply as"Becquerel fils."
  - Letter to ----, Dec. 24, 1843; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Sabbaties
    L.in 3rd.P. 2p. In French. Wishes to know if the works of Victoria Fabre are available in l'Athénée.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 13, 1844; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Becquerel, Alexandre Edmond, 1820-1891
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Wants changes made in his schedule for classes.
  - Letter to [Adolphe?] Lenoir, Paris, Oct. 22, 1846; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Madier de Montjeau, M. (Joseph-Paulin), 1785-1865
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Sympathetic letter.
  - Letter to ----, Feb. 2, 1847; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Madier de Montjeau, M. (Joseph-Paulin), 1785-1865
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks him to lecture at 3:15.
  - Letter to ----, May 1, 1847; 7-3/4x6; Mollesaut
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Presents publication.
  - Leter to ----, Feb. 2, 1849; Madier de Montjeau, M. (Joseph-Paulin), 1785-1865
  - Letter to [Adolphe?] Lenoir, Paris, May 29, 1853; 5-1/2x4; E. E.
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning a vacancy in a society. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, undated; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Andrieu, Jean Baptiste Auguste Zéphyrin, d.1819
    Monday. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French, 7-1/2x4-3/4. Etomology of a word.
  - Letter to [André Marie Constant Duméril]., undated; 10x7-1/2; Athénée des arts de Paris
    L. 2p. Draft. In French. Concerning his zoological lectures. Refers to Cuvier and Berthier.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice Goujon]., undated; 8x6; Babinet, M. (Jacques), 1794-1872
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning a course to be taught.
  - Letter to [Marie Alexandre] Lenoir, undated; 6x4; Babinet, M. (Jacques), 1794-1872
    [ca.1828]. A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Has not yet received the éloge of Fresnel. Concerning his lectures.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 4x6-1/2; Biot, Jean Baptiste, 1774-1862
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks he do a favor for a person in Lyon and made him member of the Society of antiquaries of Scotland.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier., undated; 4-1/4x6-1/2; Biot, Jean Baptiste, 1774-1862
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks for money.
  - Letter to [Léon] Duforny, undated; 7-3/4x5-1/4; Blainville, H.-M. Ducrotay de (Henri-Marie Ducrotay), 1777-1850
    Paris. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning his course on zoology which he will teach at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to Monsieur Woiselle, undated; 8x5; Blainville, H.-M. Ducrotay de (Henri-Marie Ducrotay), 1777-1850
    Paris. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning his course on natural history.
  - Letter to ----., undated; 7-1/4x5-3/4; Duhamel, M. (Jean Marie Constant), 1797-1872
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning a letter.
  - Outline of lessons he will teach at l'Athénée., undated; 7x4-3/4; Dunoyer, Charles, 1786-1862
    A.D. 2p. In French.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 7-1/4x4-3/4; Fauriel, C.C. (Claude Charles), 1772-1844
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p.and add. In French. Sends portion of book.
  - Autograph., undated; 2-3/4x6; Guillemain, Michel, 1788-1856
    A.D.S. 1p. Fragment (clipped from a letter?). In French.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier, undated; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Hassenfratz, J. H. (Jean Henri), 1755-1827
    Paris, an 9 [1800-1801]. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Apologizes for not seeing them tonight.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier., undated; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Hassenfratz, J. H. (Jean Henri), 1755-1827
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. May not be at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 4x6; Lacroix, Francois Joseph Pamphile, vicomte de, 1774-1842
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks him to visit.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier., undated; 5-1/2x4; Le Blond, Auguste-Savinien, 1760-1811
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks for tickets for lectures.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier., undated; 5-1/2x4; Le Blond, Auguste-Savinien, 1760-1811
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Needs another ticket for admission.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; Adrien de Lyon
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris]., undated; 8-1/4x6-1/4; Lingay, J. (Joseph), d. 1851
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning his publication. Concerning lectures to be presented.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris]., undated; 7-1/2x6; Lingay, J. (Joseph), d. 1851
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning courses at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to ----., undated; 8x6; Lingay, J. (Joseph), d. 1851
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Will publish his lectures.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 5x3-3/4; Matter, Jacques, 1791-1864
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks what he wishes to do after his lectures.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 7-1/2x5; Ozanam, Frédéric, 1813-1853
    A.L.S. 2p.and add. In French. Does not trust his memory enough to comment on the comments to him.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, undated; 8x4-3/4; Pagès, Etienne, 1763-1841
    Paris. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Recommends a young man to study mathematics under him.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 6-1/4x4; Pariset, Etienne, 1770-1847
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Will send him the chart tomorrow.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris]., undated; 8x5-1/4; Paris. Gazette des theatres
    A.L.S.: Cha. d'Arge. 1p. In French. Sends article on l'Athénée de Paris.
  - Letter to [l'Athénée de Paris]., undated; 8x5; Payen, Anselme, 1795-1871
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning his lectures.
  - Letter to l'Athénée de Paris, undated; 7-3/4x6-1/4; Pillet, Fabien, 1772-1855
    Mardi [Tuesday]. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning courses at l'Athénée and wishes tickets of admission.
  - Letter to Monsieur Voiselle., undated; 7-1/2x5; Pillet, Fabien, 1772-1855
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks for tickets.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 4-1/2x7-3/4; Poucelet
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Will get carton which he left on his last visit.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère., undated; 6x4; Pouillet, M. (Claude Servais Mathias), 1791-1868
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks to borrow a volume on magnetism.
  - Letter to ----., undated; 7-3/4x5; Puissant, Louis, 1769-1843
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p. In French. Asks that he deposit some publications for him.
  - Letter to [Jean Baptiste] Berthier, undated; 8-1/4x6-1/4; Ramond de Poujet, Cécile Etienne Bernard, 1756-1832
    Paris. A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning his lectures.
  - Letter to l'Athénée de Paris, Paris., undated; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Segur, Louis Philippe de, comte, 1753-1830
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. In French. Concerning his history of France.
  - Letter to [Antoine Maurice] Goujon., undated; 7-3/4x5-1/4; Simon, Léon François Adolphe, 1798-1867
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In French. Needs items for lessons at l'Athénée.
  - Letter to [Léon] Dufourny, undated; 7-1/2x6-1/4; Tracy
    Paris. A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Concerning a dispute concerning Mme de Staël and Schlegel.
  - Letter to Monsieur Woëzel, Paris, Feb. 3, undated; 8x5; Prévost, Constant, 1787-1856
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Asks for four tickets.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, Paris, June 18, undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Christien
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampére, Paris, July 19, undated; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Teysseydre
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Introduces a young doctor.
  - Letter to A[ndré Marie] Ampère, Paris, Aug. 26, undated; 10x8; Maurice, F. G. (Frédéric Guillaume), 1750-1826
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Sends mémoire of Lionville. Refers to Arago.
  - Letter to [André Marie] Ampère, August 29, undated; 8x5; Guigniault, Joseph-Daniel, 1794-1876
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. His examination for course.
  - Invitation to dinner, Sept. 25, undated; 4x7; Hachette, M. (Jean Nicolas Pierre), 1769-1834
  - Receipt to l'Athénée de Paris, December 10, undated; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Blainville, H.-M. Ducrotay de (Henri-Marie Ducrotay), 1777-1850